- Previously on "The Ark"...
- Tyson 5E.
- Whoever Maddox was meeting
might still be there
waiting for her.
- Come on over.
- I'm not the man I was.
- Something happened to Brice
as the shuttle took off.
- Is the FTL charged?
- Yeah, but...
- This ship is a safe haven
for clones.
We can be whatever we want.
- Fire EMP, Sasha.
- At what?
- "Ark 22" has left.
- Maddox was trying to help
Kurtis find a special G-44.
- What's a G-44?
- You're looking at one.
- [yells]
- Let's get the hell
off this ship.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
What the hell is going on?
- I don't know,
but we need to get moving.
- That doctor said something
about me being the one.
- Wait.
Drake's wife said
he was searching
for a special G-44 clone,
but she didn't know why.
- You talked to Drake's wife?
- Yeah, long story.
Can we get out of here now?
- There is an advantage
to looking like her.
And, I mean,
you're about his size.
- Drake to Morgan.
What's the status
of the procedure?
♪ ♪
- [clears throat]
[comm beeps]
We're about to begin, sir.
- Good.
Let's not waste any time.
My guards saw
that J6-82 from "Ark 1"
running down the corridor.
I'm sending you
two additional guards.
- We have to go.
[uplifting music]
♪ ♪
- Okay, we'll go out
the back door,
straight to the shuttle,
and radio "Ark 1" from there.
- Uh, Sharon, we're in FTL.
- Shit.
We can't detach a shuttle from
an Ark while traveling at FTL.
It will break apart.
- Wait.
I know a way,
but we need to get there first.
[breathing heavily]
- Wait.
Ian?
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
This is--
- Bad.
This is bad, but we have to go.
- What the hell
is Drake doing to them?
- Nothing good.
- [breathing heavily]
We have to do something.
- No, no, no.
Sharon, these people
are clearly Gen 3s.
They've already lost
their minds.
Look at them.
♪ ♪
- But they're still people.
We have to help them.
- Team 2,
check sector 5, 7, and 13.
- We have to go, now.
- No. No.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- [scoffs] I thought "Ark 22"
were basing themselves here.
I didn't think
that they'd leave.
- Alicia.
- There's just no way
of finding them now.
We are so screwed!
- Hey! Take a breath, okay?
- It's just--there's no way
of tracing Garnet or Ian's WD
and no way to know
where the Ark went
or even what direction
it was heading.
- Hey, I once watched you
untangle this Ark
from an alternate universe.
You can figure this out.
- That was different.
- No, you can science your way
out of anything, okay?
- Hammond is requesting
a word with you.
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- You've led us all
into grave danger.
You disobeyed my direct orders.
- You're not my captain.
- Well, your captain
left me in charge,
and now you disobeyed us both
and led the entire crew
into danger.
Do you even have a plan?
- Yes, we do.
- I heard Drake's ship's gone.
You have no idea
where they are, do you?
♪ ♪
You know, there may be
no more GSA,
but I reached a rank of admiral
through a lot of hard work
and experience.
So tell me, Lieutenant,
have you ever commanded a ship
while it was under attack?
Or launched an Ark
with 300 people
while the Earth
descended into chaos?
♪ ♪
Well, despite what you
might think about me,
I'm not
some power-hungry outsider
looking for a command.
I want to help.
So let me out,
and we can fix this together.
Or you can keep me in here,
and we all die
because of your
idiotic actions.
- I'll take that
under advisement.
♪ ♪
[WD beeps]
- Lieutenant Reed to Drake.
- Yes?
- We have a problem in Med Bay.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
- [sighs]
Impose an immediate
ship-wide lockdown.
And I want every J6-82
and G-44 identified.
[alarm beeping]
♪ ♪
- We understand
the living quarters
are a bit tight right now,
but we're working--
- Tight is an understatement.
Ever since
Eastern Federation arrived,
we've been sleeping in bunks.
- We're working on expanding
our perimeters
so we can build more housing.
- We need more generators.
Has anyone noticed that lights
have been going out
in the EF quarters
but not in the GSA cabins?
- There is no GSA
and no EF anymore.
We're all one here!
[crowd clamoring]
- Hey!
Hey, quiet down, everyone!
[door opens]
- Welcome back, Mr. Strickland.
I imagine it was a long night.
- So it was.
- Any news?
- No.
No footprints, no belongings,
not a trace.
But I haven't lost hope
of finding Angus or Kelly,
and we should not give up.
- Perhaps we should.
I don't want to put others
in danger
for such a futile cause.
- It--it's not futile.
- You just said you found
no sign of your friends.
- There's still a chance
they're alive.
It's worth
the minimal danger to--
- "Minimal danger"?
We lost two people,
vanished without a trace.
And as someone reminded us,
we all know the danger
that Kelly presents.
- I will not accept
that scenario.
We found no signs of foul play.
[scoffs]
You know what?
I'm going back out there
to search some more.
- I advise you not to.
- Who's with me?
[soft tense music]
[scoffs]
Anyone?
♪ ♪
- I'll go.
- I think they're trying
to tell us something.
- Who? Who is trying
to tell us something?
- I don't know.
- Could they be people
who worked for Mother?
- Unless she invented
some new technology,
I don't think they would have
been here long enough
to build this.
- Could another Ark have gotten
here even longer ago?
- No, not much longer.
All the Arks launched
within the same window.
- So they're aliens.
- They could be some sort
of indigenous intelligent
creatures, I guess.
Wouldn't that be cool?
- "Cool"?
They just tried
to dump us in a lava pit.
- No, they showed us
a lava pit.
That's why I think they're
trying to tell us something.
- At this point, they're going
to starve us to death.
If we don't get food soon,
we'll die.
- Water.
- What?
- If we don't get water soon,
we'll die.
We can survive at least
four more days without water,
and we can survive around
30 to 60 days without food.
- You sound like you speak
from experience.
- My family struggled a lot
back on Earth.
[soft music]
♪ ♪
We sometimes went days
without food.
- I'm sorry.
- [sniffs]
[scoffs] It's why I got
into horticulture.
♪ ♪
It felt comforting
to know I could
make food anywhere...
anytime.
[rumbling]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
- Why would they give us
a bunch of rocks?
- Maybe they think
that's what we eat.
♪ ♪
[indistinct chatter]
- Mmm.
How's your salad?
Mine's great.
I guess, uh...
the sunshine
actually makes a difference.
But, um, I'd die
for a steak right now.
[sighs]
Sanji...
I'm sorry.
Look, I don't--I don't know
what else to say.
I know I overstepped
the other day--
- "Overstepped"?
I told you that I needed
to handle it myself,
and then you immediately went
and threatened him.
You don't understand
how it feels to go through--
[somber music]
♪ ♪
- Did you know they were--
Sanji.
Sanji, please, wait.
- I just--
I really don't want
to get involved,
but if Ves is
in a relationship with--
she should know
about my past with him.
- I agree.
- But it's really none
of my business.
- [sighs]
You want me to talk to her?
- No!
It's definitely not
your business.
- [sighs]
Okay, look...
[chuckles]
I'm just trying to figure
this out, just like you.
- I--
I have to do this
on my own, okay?
- [sighs]
♪ ♪
[doors whir]
- Thought I might
find you here.
I brought you the new drink
from the bar.
The Homebase Highball.
- Really?
- Mm.
A sweet and very strong drink
is the last thing
they should be serving
if they're trying
to ease tensions.
But it might be just the thing
for someone who's feeling,
I don't know,
a bit down in the dumps.
- Thanks,
but I really need to focus.
- Still concocting impossible
theories about Brice's death?
- Come look at this.
[device beeps]
I was able to zoom in
and enhance
"Ark 1's" high-res hull cameras
to see his death
from a different angle.
- You really like putting
yourself through hell,
don't you?
- Look, his body
definitely disappeared.
But if he was dragged away
by a creature, like you said,
we would see drag marks,
and there aren't any, so--
- The ground is hard.
Drag marks wouldn't show,
or they've been blown away.
- Or he walked away.
- Eva, I know you're looking
for answers,
but maybe it's time to admit
there just aren't any.
You should spend your time
doing something
that might actually result
in something good.
[explosion]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
- It's been over two hours.
Please tell me
you've made some progress.
- I have.
I've been analyzing
the spectral emissions
from a trace amount of ionized
particles left behind
by "Ark 22" to determine
which direction it went.
- And?
- The results are inconclusive,
but I'm confident
it will lead to something soon.
- Okay, how soon?
- I don't know.
- We can't keep the whole crew
stranded here forever.
- No one said forever.
- Well, then how long are you
gonna try to figure this out
before we give up
and head back to Homebase?
- "Give up"?
We're not giving up.
What did Hammond say to you?
- Nothing.
It's just...
we can only do this for so long
before we have to move on,
Alicia.
♪ ♪
[alarm beeping]
- Hey, Mike!
You on for poker tonight?
- Oh, yeah. Sure am, buddy.
Yeah.
- All right.
- "Buddy"?
- I panicked.
[device beeping, chimes]
♪ ♪
- Okay.
We'll wait
for the guard to pass,
and then we got a straight shot
to the shuttle.
- Uh, Sharon?
♪ ♪
I guess they're making
new clones.
♪ ♪
- Coast is clear.
Come on.
- Could you give me more space?
- No, actually, I can't.
- I'm working
as fast as I can. I--
[beeps]
Oh, no.
- What?
- I've been locked out. I--
[beeps]
What the hell? So have I.
- Are the GSA override codes
still active?
- I'm not sure.
- They sure are.
All right, kids, fun's over.
- How did you get out?
- [scoffs] I've been doing this
a long time.
I'm a trained soldier.
That guard you put on me
was not.
He went down far too easy.
- Please, Admiral,
we can't just leave--
- I gave you a chance.
Now we're doing things my way.
♪ ♪
- Hey!
Where do you think
you're going?
- Uh, we got an alert to check
on some noise near the hatch.
- With the doctor?
- We thought
someone might be hurt.
- I'll scan you first.
- Hey.
Uh, whoa, is that necessary?
- Please remain where you are
and look into the device.
- Oh, no need for that,
Mark, dear.
They're with me.
- Mrs. Drake,
we have strict orders
to check all G-44s and J6-82s.
- I understand that.
But I'm telling you,
it's not necessary.
- Come on.
You're not really gonna dismiss
Kurtis Drake's wife, are you?
Huh?
- [chuckles]
Listen, I'll happily call
my husband,
if that's what you want.
Is that what you want?
- No.
[clears throat]
No, it's--it's fine.
- Toodle-oo.
- [giggles]
- Thanks for that.
Uh, Clark, I presume.
- Oh, just call me brother.
- [giggles]
- I'm good.
- Why are you helping us?
- Because we want you
to take us with you,
away from my husband.
We're--we're in love,
and we'd rather not keep
sneaking around.
- Or get thrown
out the airlock,
which will likely happen
if we stay here, so...
- Well, taking you with us
is a risk.
Why should we?
- If you do, we'll tell you
everything you want to know,
starting with why you should
really try some pink lipstick.
It does wonders
for our complexion.
[giggles]
- Please, I know I can
figure out where they are.
If you could just give me
more time, then--
- You've had enough time.
Frankly, I regret
not locking you out sooner.
- But I know--
- Enough!
I wanted you to see
for yourself
how improbable your plan was,
but the fact that you still
can't see it is alarming.
Set a course for Homebase 1.
We're going home.
♪ ♪
Look...
I am not making
this decision lightly,
but I think you all know
this is what Captain Garnet
would want.
♪ ♪
And she left me in charge.
- I'll only take orders
from someone I trust.
That would be Alicia or Garnet.
- I feel the same way.
- This is ridiculous.
I'll do it myself.
- Please, Admiral,
if you respect the GSA mores,
then you know that we can't--
- I'm done arguing about this!
- We won't take orders
from you!
- Stand down!
- Wait, stop! Stop!
I think we should listen
to Admiral Hammond.
- What?
- Look, I don't want to leave
our friends behind.
You know I don't, but we don't
have a plan to find them,
and even if you had all
the time in the world, Alicia,
it's still a needle
in the giant haystack of space.
We should go back to Homebase.
I think it's what
Captain Garnet would do,
don't you?
[solemn music]
♪ ♪
- Yeah.
Yeah.
♪ ♪
- What happened?
Generators don't just explode
without reason.
- Well, people are saying
former EF engineers
illegally tried to reroute
the electricity
to their quarters.
They just blew up the generator
by accident.
- Well, other people are saying
that former GSA engineers
were doing the opposite.
- What do we know?
- Not much.
Just that this was
a targeted attack,
which means
that it wasn't accidental.
- How do you know?
- I tested the residue
on the generator.
It's made of an explosive
compound called trillium.
- Trillium?
Where would someone get access
to that?
- That's just it--
trillium is too volatile
to be carried on Arks.
So we don't know
who brought it here or how.
- What we do know
is that whoever did this
wanted to create a large
and deadly explosion.
[tablet chiming]
- What do you know
about trillium...
Mr. Avega?
- "Mr. Avega."
It's Captain,
and the answer is nothing.
EF ships don't carry it
for the same reason as Arks.
- Can you prove that?
- What are you implying?
- Nothing.
I'm just asking a question.
- Well, I could ask you
the same question.
Did someone from GSA bring it?
Maybe this Maddox person
I keep hearing about?
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
- Dr. Kabir?
- Hi, Ves.
Uh...
[clears throat]
May I call you Ves?
- Well, that's what
everyone else is calling me.
- [chuckles awkwardly]
- How may I help you, Doctor?
- Um, I was hoping that
we could speak in private.
It's a personal matter.
- So is this about Milan?
- Uh, I'm--I'm not sure
what he told you, but--
- That you used to be married.
- Yes.
- It sounds like it was
a difficult relationship.
- Uh, that's one way
of putting it.
[chuckles awkwardly]
- Well, some people just don't
fit together, I suppose.
- Yeah, well, um, this was
more than that.
Um...
Milan had a pretty severe
drinking problem
and was abusive.
- He quit drinking
when he came on "Ark 11."
He's been sober ever since.
- I'm glad to hear that.
- I know Milan.
I was on an Ark with him
for over two years.
I guess that's at least...
a year longer than you were
married to him, right?
♪ ♪
- Um, did he ever tell you
how we met?
- He didn't tell me
much at all about you.
- Oh.
♪ ♪
I was sitting on a bus...
heading home from a late shift
at the hospital.
He came over
and sat next to me,
struck up a conversation,
and within two minutes,
he said he knew
we would get married.
And I knew...
he was right.
- Is there a point?
- Yeah.
The point is that...
I know how charming he can be.
You know when the last time
I saw Milan was?
When he watched me drive away
and he put his fist
through a wall.
I applied for "Ark 1"
without telling him.
When I got accepted,
I left as fast as I could
with whatever I could pack.
I had to go to frickin' space
to get away from him.
- Aw.
- [scoffs]
Okay.
I just thought
you should know that.
[breathing heavily]
♪ ♪
[chiming and beeping]
- Well, Generator B is secure.
The control panel
needed fixing,
if you can believe that.
You know, doing your work for
you is well below my pay grade,
but I have to say,
there is something thrilling
about going back to basics.
It reminds me how brilliant
and generous I am.
- That's nice.
- So did you hear we voted
and we're gonna turn Homebase
into a nudist colony?
- Mm-hmm.
Sounds good.
- Well...
- Yeah.
- Markovic!
You haven't listened to a word
I've said, have you?
- I'm sorry.
I'm just focused.
- On what?
- I triangulated
a repeating signal
coming from Ross.
It could be a transmission.
- It's an automated
distress beacon.
All Arks have them.
That one's coming from "Ark 4."
If you check back
on the SAV logs,
you've probably been
getting it for days.
- I did check the logs.
It started
right after "Ark 1" left Ross.
- Well, there could be
a dozen reasons for that,
none of them to do
with human intervention.
- Still, it's possible.
- Have you done your work
on Generator C?
- Not yet.
- I'll do it.
I'm just becoming
such a good person.
- Yeah, good people
don't say stuff like that.
- [scoffs]
So now you're listening to me.
[jazzy music]
♪ ♪
[chuckles]
There you are.
I've been looking
all over for you, Doctor.
- What do you want, Mr. Trust?
- Tell me, have you tried
the Homebase Highball?
It's a delicious drink.
- I'm an addict, remember?
This is water.
- I thought that was pills,
not spirits.
- Well, I'm not about to trade
one addiction for another.
- So why are you sat at a bar,
of all places?
- I don't know, I always used
to go to the bar for a drink
after a bad day on Earth.
I guess old habits, you know?
- Mmm.
Oh, you really need
to taste this.
Uh, right.
Never mind.
- Why were you looking for me?
- Well, you know, I'm normally
completely oblivious
to other people's emotions.
Well, I believe--
- Don't worry. I'll be fine.
- No, I'm talking about Eva.
- Eva?
- Yes.
Poor woman--
she spends all her hours
watching and rewatching
the video
of the Scotsman's death.
- Yeah, I-I know it's been
really hard on her.
- Yes, and I was hoping
that you could give her
some kind of pill
to make it stop.
She's getting
absolutely no work done.
- [scoffs] You know,
there's no pill for grief.
She's just gonna have to work
through it her way.
It will take time.
- How long?
- You know,
I'm glad you care so much
for Eva's well-being,
Mr. Trust.
- No, this time
I'm talking about you.
How long do you think
you're gonna be down
in the proverbial dumps?
- Uh, don't worry.
I'll be fine.
- Okay, because, uh,
you know, a lot of people
need you and...
care for you.
And I don't know
if you want to...
talk about whatever that is
or something.
- Um...
[scoffs]
No, it--it--it's complicated.
- Oh, well, I'm best
at complicated.
[both laugh]
But, actually,
that's, uh, more applied
to physics than human emotion.
But--but should you ever
need someone to talk to--
- Thank you.
♪ ♪
[tense music]
- Could it be a threat?
Like, they'll break us
into little pieces
if we don't behave?
- [scoffs] That's a bit
extreme, don't you think?
- No.
They literally kidnapped us
and imprisoned us
inside a cave.
- I'm just saying,
maybe they're trying
to say something more nuanced.
Wait a second.
♪ ♪
Look at this.
Look, look!
It's like some--
it's like some kind of puzzle.
There.
Uh...
there.
[rumbling]
♪ ♪
Oh!
Okay.
That feels like progress.
- Did you send a man
to secure the generator?
- No, I didn't send anyone.
- Then who's that, then?
[ominous music]
- Hey, you.
- Uh, excuse me.
You're not supposed to be here.
- Hey, hey, hey!
[both grunting]
- Back away, Sheriff!
- What?
- Back away!
Get out of here!
[explosion]
- All right, you said
you knew a way to drop
this hunk of metal
out of an FTL bubble.
Now's the time.
- Yeah, well, first off,
let's not call her
a hunk of metal,
'cause we're gonna want her
on our side.
- What's the plan?
- I'm gonna rig
our impulse coils
to pull from the Ark
FTL retrofit
and give us our own
temporary bubble.
Just give me a minute.
- Wait, wait, wait.
Is this something you knew
before the coma dream
or something you learned
inside the dream?
- We did it once on "Ark 8."
- And it worked?
- Sort of.
- "Sort of"?
- Well, aren't you two just
a good-looking little couple?
- We are, aren't we?
I'm sure you're aware,
but J6-82s are known
for their animal magnetism.
- We are, you know, which means
you got it, too, my friend.
- [giggles]
- Good to know.
How long you two been
together, then?
- Oh, about one year,
six months.
But who's counting?
- I met Clark just when
I thought my life was over,
when I found out
my husband was sleeping
with three different G-44s.
- Ouch.
So he has a type, then,
does he?
- Can you blame him?
We're gorgeous.
- Well, that goes
without saying.
[both laugh]
- Right, you two
better buckle in tight.
It's gonna be a bumpy ride.
Okay, drop us out of here.
- Are you sure this will work?
- Not at all.
- Ian!
- Well, it probably will.
- "Probably"?
- Yes, there's a good chance
it will work.
But then again,
we might die, so...
[soft music]
- Wow, I--
- Sorry, I just--
boundaries, I know,
but also maybe death, so...
- Are you ready?
- Let's do this.
♪ ♪
[exhales sharply]
Okay.
[breathing heavily]
- Hang on.
Detaching from "Ark 22"
in three, two, one.
[exciting music]
- [laughs]
- Hang on.
♪ ♪
- Come on.
Come on! Come on!
- [grunts]
- [yelps]
- Whoa, whoa!
[rumbling]
- What was that?
- It appears we lost FTL
bubble integrity for a moment,
but it's been reestablished.
[alarm beeps]
- Sir, uh, the "Ark 1" shuttle
is gone.
[dramatic music]
- Full stop...
now.
- Setting a course
for Homebase 1.
[computer pings]
- Wait.
♪ ♪
We just received a distress
ping from our shuttle.
- That means Garnet
and Ian are alive!
- Hope you're not trying
to pull something, crewman.
- See for yourself.
- Did a message come
with the signal?
- It was just a ping,
but it came on an encrypted
"Ark 1"-only channel.
- It has to be them!
- Or it's a trap.
- Nobody else
could have sent it.
They'd need
Captain Garnet's code.
- That was insane.
- I can't believe
the bloody thing worked.
[both laugh]
- Now Alicia just has
to triangulate to the ping.
Are you guys all right
back there?
- We're fine.
- Wait, wait.
What if "Ark 22" finds us
before Alicia does?
- They won't. I sent the ping
under "Ark 1" encryption.
"Ark 22" won't even see
the signal.
[rumbling]
- Are you sure about that?
- How the hell did he find us?
- We're sitting ducks.
♪ ♪
- Drake won't fire on us.
His doctor told me I'm the one.
He needs me for a reason.
- Maybe,
but does he need you alive?
♪ ♪
[computer pings]
- Yes.
[gasps]
I did it.
- You have the coordinates?
- I know where they are.
♪ ♪
All right.
[keys clacking]
- There seemed to be
a misunderstanding.
Why don't you come back to my
ship and we can talk it over?
- How did you find us?
- You keep underestimating me.
I simply traced where
the FTL disruption took place,
and here you are.
♪ ♪
[rumbling]
- Sharon.
[exciting music]
[both laugh]
- Oh, they came back for you.
How nice.
Good people.
[ominous music]
Lock all weapons onto that Ark.
- No.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
- Whoa, whoa!
What are you doing?
- The closer we get to "Ark 1,"
the less likely
they'll fire on them.
A stray blast
could kill us, too.
He won't risk losing me
to destroy them.
[dramatic music]
- Ms. Nevins, fire EM pulse!
What are you waiting for?
Fire before they fire on us!
- The EM pulse
is not directional.
It'll disable the shuttle, too.
- I knew this was a bad idea.
Go to FTL!
- No, Kimi, don't.
- Do it, Lieutenant Joma.
- I think
with all your experience,
you'd know it takes time
to recharge FTL, Admiral.
♪ ♪
- Can you get a clean shot
on "Ark 1"
without hitting the shuttle?
- Yes, from our
starboard cannon.
- Perfect. Then fire.
- Really?
They didn't do anything to us.
- Fire.
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
- [gasps, grunts]
[victorious music]
- Come on!
[both laugh]
♪ ♪
- Well, don't look
so surprised.
I scienced it.
- Initiating
docking sequence now!
♪ ♪
- Oh, yes!
The shuttle is docked
and locked.
[chuckles]
♪ ♪
- They charged up
just in time, I guess.
♪ ♪
- Good work, Ms. Nevins.
[both laugh]
[both moan]
- I love you.
- You're my only.
[both moaning]
- You have to admit, they do
look kind of good together,
don't they?
- [laughs]
[both moaning]
- Oh, Clark.
- I just can't be without you.
- [breathing heavily, giggles]
- Two incoming!
Sheriff Petrovic
and an unknown male.
- "Unknown"?
- No ID.
No one recognizes him,
but they say he's the guy
who caused the explosions.
- Um, I'll take John Doe.
- Scanner.
- Neuro scan.
- I'm gonna need a CBC
and CMP on both.
- And start IV fluids, stat.
Who the hell is this guy?
- Help. Dr. Kabir.
I need medical attention
before I bleed out.
- From the scratch
on your elbow?
Give Mr. Trust a Band-Aid
and a lollipop.
- Head injury here.
No other major trauma.
- Yeah, I can't say
the same here.
Hemoglobin is dropping,
and he's got
extensive hemorrhaging.
- Hold on, Dr. Kabir.
I recognize these clothes.
This is what Angus was wearing
the last time I saw him.
- The T-shirt is inside out.
♪ ♪
What the hell?
[keys clacking]
[knock at door]
- It's open.
- You wanted to see us,
Captain?
- Yes, come in.
Close the door.
[sighs]
I thought you should know,
Admiral Hammond told me
what you did.
Actually, he came
to me to report
he wasn't gonna press
court martial charges
for what you did.
- About that--
- It was my idea.
- I told him,
since there is no GSA,
there is
no court martial authority.
But just the same,
I thought you should know
he wouldn't have
pressed charges anyway.
- Well, I guess that's good.
He doesn't hate us.
- He would have been right
to charge us, though.
- Damn straight he would have.
You disregarded a direct order
by your commanding officer,
one I left in charge
of this ship,
so you also disregarded
my order.
- Yes, ma'am, I'm prepared
to step aside from my duties.
- That won't be necessary.
The whole point of this
is to say I expect both of you
to obey orders
while on this ship.
- Yes, ma'am.
- I will.
- Uh, is that all?
- Yes.
No, one more thing.
Thank you for being stubborn,
insubordinate women
who refuse to give up
on someone they care about.
[soft music]
It means a lot.
- [chuckles]
- Now get in here.
- Angus!
Angus!
Look, they kind of had
a point back there.
How long do we keep searching?
- Until we find them.
- You must be exhausted.
- I'm fine.
- How's your daughter doing?
- She's staying
with a friend from school--
an endless sleepover,
as far as she's concerned.
- Yeah, I remember those days,
when any problem could be fixed
with a playdate
and an ice cream cone.
[chuckles]
Just wait
till she's a teenager.
- I try not to think
about that.
- Yeah, nothing scarier
than a teenage girl...
except a sociopath
with superhuman implants.
Look, I know
you disagree, but--
- Kelly did not kill
or hurt Angus.
- You don't know that.
- And you don't know
that she did.
- Well, I know that you
don't have another theory
about what happened.
- [sighs]
You're right, I have nothing...
which only means
we're missing something.
- Something like...
this?
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
- What the hell is that?
- Oh, sorry.
It's just--Ian, I've seen
a clone of you before,
but not you, Sharon.
- [chuckles]
It's bizarre, I know.
- I mean,
you're just so identical.
I mean, minus the hair
and the jewelry and the makeup.
[laughs]
- She could use some lipstick.
Trust me, I told her.
[both laugh]
- Lipstick or not,
she's beautiful
'cause she looks like you.
- [chuckles] See that?
Always a charmer.
Tell me, are you as madly
in love with yours
as I am with mine?
- Oh, we're--
- Yeah. No, no, no,
we're not--we're not a thing.
She's my boss.
- Yeah.
- So what? I was his boss.
I mean, well, my husband was.
- So you're in love
with this guy,
but you're married to Drake?
- Was. I...
I prefer to think of,
was married to Drake.
- So do you have any idea
what he's after?
Why does he want these two?
- And why was there a room
full of clones like you and me?
- So many questions.
[laughs]
[dramatic music]
What it all comes down to
is this...
my husband says you're the one.
- That's what
the doctor said, too.
- Hmm.
- What the hell does that mean?
- It means you're the Gen 3
he's been searching for
ever since we launched.
- I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm not Gen 3.
- Yes, darling, you are.
♪ ♪
- You let her get away.
- They had shields.
- You should have found a way
around them.
- I tried, but--
- You tried?
She's gone, you understand?
And we don't even know
where Homebase 1 is.
Evelyn would never tell me.
You have to find Homebase 1.
- How?
No planet in the database
is called Homebase.
- They obviously named it
themselves,
so search all possible
habitable planets
until you find it!
- That could take a year or--
- I don't care!
♪ ♪
Find her.
[thunder,
electricity crackling]